MERT YAZİCİ

Karşıyaka İzmir • 531 790 36 06 • yazici.mert.35@gmail.com www.mertyazici.dev • GitHub • Linkedin

SUMMARY

During the pandemic, I discovered my interest in software development and focused heavily on this field through individual studies. In 2021, I started my professional career in the software industry as an SEO Consultant at Kriko Bilişim. To support my development and apply the experience I gained, I began creating websites as a freelance developer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

2023 - Now

• I designed and developed user-friendly and functional websites tailored to customer needs.

Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Provided consultancy services to major brands, focusing on e-commerce websites and achieving significant performance improvements for both B2B and B2C businesses.
- Executed comprehensive SEO strategies encompassing technical SEO and various other aspects of search engine optimization.
- Utilized industry-leading tools such as SEMrush, Searchmetrics, and Ahrefs to drive data-driven SEO campaigns.
- Developed and implemented on-page and off-page SEO strategies to enhance website visibility and organic traffic.
- Monitored and reported on SEO performance metrics, providing actionable insights for continuous improvement.
- Worked proficiently with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create landing pages and simple designed websites.

Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

• Issued and marketed insurance policies.

EDUCATION

Department of Banking and Insurance

2010 - 2013

Anadolu University

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Languages: English (intermediate)
- Certifications:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. IBM Cybersecurity Fundamentals
- 3. IBM Working in a Digital World: Professional Skills
- 4. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu Sinan Mutlu & Taha Selim Aksakal
- 5. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 6. Udemy Web Development HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP. NET Core